# ALESSANDRO FRONDINI

#### JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### CONTACT

07490 403 776

alessandrofrondini@gmail.com

github.com/alessandro-001

in <u>alefrondini</u>

Manchester

alessandrofrondini.netlify.app/

#### TECH STACK

- Javascript
- React
- HyperText Markup Language (HTML5) TailwindCSS
- Cascading StyleSheets (CSS3)
- Express
- Structured Query Language (SQL)
- PostgreSQL
- Firebase



Typescript

Material UI

React Native

# ABOUT ME

I am a native Italian living in Manchester UK, I've always been fascinated by technology and how it can transform the world. The flexibility and constant evolution of this field inspired me to change my career from dental technology to software development.

As I transition from the dental world to the tech industry, I am driven by my genuine passion for the field and a strong work ethic. I highly value teamwork and believe in the power of collaboration. Moreover, I am enthusiastic about finding a company that can teach me new skills, while also showcasing flexibility and upholding high standards, traits that I believe will be invaluable to achieving success.

My heart lies in the realm of front-end development, where my passion for precision and attention to detail, honed from my previous job as a dental technician, inspires me to create thoughtful user experiences.

Additionally, my soft skills, such as effective time management, maintaining quality standards and staying organised will fully contribute to get the job done.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Junior Software Developer

March 2023 - June 2023

Northcoders, Manchester, UK

- Successfully completed Northcoders' intensive full stack software developer bootcamp, gaining a solid foundation in programming and proficiency in various languages essential for web development.
- · Acquired valuable skills through agile methodologies and sprints in JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, and React
- Experienced Firebase, React Native, TypeScript, and Tailwind CSS, integrating these technologies into the final project to enhance functionality and design. Direct link: github.com/alessandro-001/Love-Birds-App

## **Prosthodontics Dental Technician**

August 2018 - March 2023

Dentco ltd, Warrington, UK

- All around dental technician in a private dental clinic, manufacturing of complete and partial acrylic dentures, dental repairs and additions
- · Patients and dentists work coordinator and use of Labtrac database system for patient record keeping.

# EDUCATION

September 2015 - June 2018

## BSc (Honors) Dental Technology - 1st Class Honours

Manchester Metropolitan University

- I developed strong working skills during laboratory sessions and various formal projects on Denture and Dental prosthetic design
  that required significant problem solving skills, strong technical abilities and professionalism in collaborating with colleagues and
  patients
- Extensive research project completed on the Antimicrobial Efficacy of Graphene Oxide and Graphene Oxide + Silver Particles Incorporated into an Acrylic Denture Soft Liner.

#### **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

As a culinary enthusiast, I am passionate about exploring diverse cuisines and embarking on culinary adventures through trying out new recipes. Inspired by the places I have visited, I find great joy in incorporating the flavours and techniques of different cultures into my cooking repertoire. It allows me to create unique and exciting culinary experiences that reflect my love for both travel and gastronomy.